Clement Fung

Email: clement.y.fung@gmail.com
Website: https://clementfung.github.io/

SUMMARY

My current research interests include the security and privacy of distributed systems. Most notably, I am interested in distributed multi-party machine learning and corresponding attacks and defenses on these system. Lately, I am especially interested in the security and privacy issues surrounding Google's federated learning.

PUBLICATIONS

Non-refereed publications

- Muhammad Shayan, **Clement Fung**, Chris J.M. Yoon, Ivan Beschastnikh. Biscotti: A Ledger for Private and Secure Peer-to-Peer Machine Learning. arXiv November 2018.
- Clement Fung, Jamie Koerner, Stewart Grant, Ivan Beschastnikh.

 Dancing in the Dark: Private Multi-Party Machine Learning in an Untrusted Setting.

 arXiv November 2018.
- Clement Fung, Chris J.M. Yoon, Ivan Beschastnikh. *Mitigating Sybils in Federated Learning Poisoning*. arXiv August 2018.

EDUCATION

MSc, Computer Science

2016 - 2018

University of British Columbia, Vancouver, BC Cumulative GPA: 88 / 100

Thesis:

• Dancing in the Dark: Private Multi-Party Machine Learning in an Untrusted Setting. Supervisor: Ivan Beschastnikh

Achievements:

- UBC CS Department Graduate Teaching Assistant Award, 2017
- UBC CS Department Student Service Award, 2017

Research Projects:

- Biscotti: A secure, private blockchain-based system for multi-party machine learning
- FoolsGold: A sybil-resilient federated learning protocol against model poisoning
- TorMentor: A system for distributed, collaborative, anonymous machine learning
- InsuLearn: A system for distributed learning on private medical data
- DistributedClocks: A library for vector clock instrumentation of distributed systems

Graduate Courses:

• CPSC 532R - Graphical Models (*Prof. Siamak Ravanbakhsh*)

- CPSC 540 Advanced Machine Learning (*Prof. Mark Schmidt*)
- CPSC 538W Data At Scale (*Prof. Andrew Warfield*)
- CPSC 538B Distributed Systems (*Prof. Ivan Beschastnikh*)
- CPSC 536F Algorithmic Game Theory (*Prof. Hu Fu*)
- CPSC 340 Machine Learning (*Prof. Mark Schmidt*)

BASc, Honours, Systems Design Engineering

2011 - 2016

University of Waterloo, Waterloo, ON Cumulative GPA: 88 / 100

Achievements:

- Sanford Fleming Award for Co-operative Proficiency Achievement in Co-op and Academics
- Graduated with Dean's Honour's Distinction 4x Dean's List
- Dean's Honour's List, Winter 2016
- Dean's Honour's List, Winter 2013 Ranked 2nd / 81 students
- Dean's Honour's List, Spring 2012 Ranked 2nd / 85 students
- Dean's Honour's List, Fall 2011 Ranked 3rd / 94 students

Awards:

- W.W. King Exchange Fellowship, Winter 2015 \$500
- President's International Experience Award, Winter 2014 \$1500
- Sanford Fleming Award, Fall 2013, Outstanding Communication in Work Term Report \$300
- Colonel Hugh Heasley Engineering Scholarship, Fall 2011 \$10000
- University of Waterloo President's Scholarship of Distinction, Fall 2011 \$2000

Research Projects:

- Driven: A system for intelligent annotation and analysis of lane changes based on dashcam videos
- FridgeMate: A mobile application and intelligent image recognition system for annotation of food in refrigerators

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant	Sept 2016 - Dec 2018
University of British Columbia	

DSCI 571: Supervised Learning Instructory Mileshael Calkert Versele Kelhetler	Fall 2018
Instructor: Mikchael Gelbart, Varada Kolhatkar • DSCI 523: Data Wrangling	Fall 2018
Instructor: Jenny Bryan, Rodolfo Lourenzutti	W. 1 0010

• CPSC 340: Machine Learning	Winter 2018
Instructor: Michael Gelbart	

• CPSC 340: Machine Learning	Fall 2017
Instructor: Mark Schmidt	

• CPSC 210: Software Construction	Winter 2017
Instructors: Norman Hutchinson, Paul Carter, Mehrdad Oveisi	

CPSC 210: Software Construction	Fall 2016
Instructors: Norman Hutchinson, Ryan Vogt, Jonatan Schroeder	

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineering Intern

Oasis Labs, Berkeley, CA, USA

• Working on an early stage privacy-preserving blockchain

Software Engineering Intern

June - August 2015

January 2019 - present

LinkedIn Corporation, Sunnyvale, CA, USA

• Analytics: Building infrastructure for online relevance scoring at scale

Software Engineering Intern

September 2014 - December 2014

LinkedIn Corporation, Mountain View, CA, USA

• Distributed Data Systems: Prototyped and designed new derived data serving system, Venice

Software Engineering Intern

January 2014 - April 2014

Voicebox Technologies, Bellevue, WA, USA

• Server and Tools: Implemented layer for concurrent database access on a mobile service

Software Developer

May 2013 - August 2013

Ontario Institute for Cancer Research, Toronto, ON

• Software developer in Paul Boutros' bioinformatics research group

Software Developer

September 2012 - December 2012

pVelocity, Toronto, ON

QA Analyst

January 2012 - April 2012

pVelocity, Toronto, ON